Support for NPR comes from Moises, the creative suite for musicians, used by over 75 million artists worldwide to learn, create and collaborate, available for phone, tablet and desktop.
This is the only thing I wanted for this album. This is it. This is all I wanted.
This is, yeah, this is amazing.
I'm here with my band.
I'm here with Ricky, who I made the whole album with.
Ricky Gormet, Matt Fildi, whatever you want to call him,
he goes by many names.
This next song is about feeling annoyed by having a crush
because I often do.
I find it really annoying to be distracted by one person,
especially a guy.
Um, and...
Let's do it. Let's sing it.
I'm taking first drops in the battery.
Get you in the trenches.
Come to your senses.
Stay place so vacant and on the grip.
I think I look bad but it does.
I once read that some people's beauty can't be captured.
And he'll be sorry.
Happy ever after.
Here's what I want to say right now is I've been on tour
and I do Q&A's before shows.
And I get asked all the time, who's
your favorite friend's character?
What is your favorite friend's episode?
And it's a fair question because I wrote a song about one
of the characters from friends that I'm going to play next.
But the truth is I've seen all but one and a half seasons.
I saw what I needed to see.
I got what I needed.
I wrote the song and I think it's a great show.
I wouldn't commemorate something that I didn't think was truly iconic.
But if you come to my Q&A, just feel free to not ask me that anymore.
And thank you for coming to my Q&A.
Alrighty.
I took a walk on the beach, oh exciting.
Keep it truck and show me.
One quick sec.
Steve, Steve.
You know, I don't often get embarrassed,
and I think that's something that people may be caught on,
too about me, and I think, you know,
that's great if that's your perception,
but I do get embarrassed about one thing specifically,
and it's been a running theme as I've been on the road.
I am really truly embarrassed by how
shoked up I get when I soundcheck sometimes.
It's like, it feels embarrassing.
And it's always this specific song that gets me
because I have very, very vivid memories of writing it.
And it was before I kind of knew that I was going to go down this path
of singer songwriter.
And this song is the reason why I
chose to do this because when I finished writing it I thought I have to sing this.
And it took me a long time to write and every time I sing it I do get, not every time,
but a lot.
I get emotional.
I'm not going to right now though because I really want to nail it.
So yes, it's called Sex in the City.
This isn't Sex in the City.
Nobody's watching me write in the room.
And anyway when I get on my take off my cool clothes
Cause while I would stay in those
I go to the bar that's monumental
And if he's hard and seems in to it it's accidental
What's it like to be admired?
Hard and desired, this isn't sex in the city
Nobody sees me in those of my calling
Nobody sees me at all is the problem
But of course when they do, they're not the one that don't want you but a go to the bar
On in the stars then I don't want it either
I say goodbye and take the bottle
I've never been stronger
Could you turn this to travel if I've stole?
In the city, it's already called me
But instead I'm in the shower
Got a feeling warm touch song
Now I'm ready to go back out and easier at the bar
God is he boring, but make up with him in the morning
He calls a car to his appointment
I guess there's a God then
The seat is up, the place is haunted
He's heating up and eating up a pizza pocket
I want it one, I'm ready for God it
He's off his meds, and he's an artist touching my leg
You don't have a if this is it, and what is it all for?
Let's make it quick and believe in that she's both.
Sometimes when you're burgeoning artist, you have one hit.
I would classify this as a hit, and I also think it's only a hit with time.
Because it's time that makes it a hit.
So, seeing 10 years.
Five years.
Scene five.
Three.
It's the first song we made together.
We made all this music in his really hot studio apartment.
It was 100 degrees.
We'd have cold rags and bowls just around our neck, making
the song, which is called Suomi.
Can you sing along here?
I just think along if you want.
OK.
Sorry, I know you remember.
Are you depressed or are you feeling better?
Because they say class.
Thanks so much for watching.
Support for In-Pear Music comes from Moises, committed
to ethical innovation and empowering the creative community
with tools for musicians to master their craft.